没错  亲爱的  米奇尔帮我
Yeah, honey, Mitchell helped me
挑的衬衫  你会喜欢的
pick up the shirt. You're gonna love it.
我也希望能帮你买唇膏
Oh, I wish I could pick you up some lip gloss
但我们已经在车里了
but we are already at the car.
好吧  再见  亲爱的
Okay, bye, honey.
弹得不错吧
Getting pretty good, huh?
是啊  你一向很厉害
Yeah, but you were always good.
我很高兴你坚持学下来了
I'm just glad you stuck with it.
你认真的吗
Seriously?
怎么了
What?
这琴自己在弹
It's playing itself.
我又不知道
I didn't know.
你真的以为我突然成了钢琴大师吗  爸
You honestly thought that I just became a piano virtuoso, dad?
你看着我从小长到大
You knew my whole life.
你看过我学琴了吗
Have you ever seen me take a lesson?
我以为你自学了呢
I thought maybe you were self-taught.
抱歉  你说得对
Oh, I'm sorry. You're right.
-就像我自学单簧管一样  -没错
- Like when I taught myself to play the clarinet. - Exactly.
我从没吹过单簧管
I never played the clarinet.
能别说了吗
Can we drop it?
我们去吃个冰淇淋吧
Let's go get an ice cream.
考虑过我乳糖不耐受吗
What about my lactose intolerance?
我不太喜欢这样纠缠下去
Oh, I'm not loving this game.
太糟糕了
This sucks.
我老师给了我单核细胞增多症
My teacher gave me mononucleosis.
[单核细胞增多症: 一种通过接吻传染的疾病]
作为父母  我觉得我有必要问清楚
As a parent, I feel I should ask about this.
别去阻止  她想吸引男人也不容易
Slow down. It's not like she gets that many tugs on the line.
是生物课作业
It's for A.P. Bio.
我们得写关于一种疾病的报告
We have to write a report about a disease,
我拿到了最糟糕的题目  简直开玩笑
and I got the worst one. This is a joke.
其实那种病很严重
Actually, it's pretty serious.
上大学时  我从我室友林那里
Back in college, I caught mono
感染了单细胞增多症
from my roommate, Ling.
是我们鬼混应得的报应
Served us right for fooling around.
不要跟别人同吹一根长笛  孩子们
Never share a flute, kids.
你能载我到图书馆吗
Hey, can you drop me off at the library?
抱歉  我要去湖边的咖啡馆见朋友
Sorry. I'm meeting some friends at that coffee shop on lake.
你是说图书馆旁边那家吗
You mean the one next to the library?
那是图书馆吗
That's a library?
我还以为那是某个
I thought it was a church
不允许化妆的宗教的教堂呢
for a religion that didn't allow makeup.
洗衣机什么时候才能修好啊
When is the washing machine gonna get fixed?
我裤子底下穿着泳裤呢
I'm wearing a swimsuit underneath my pants.
大家很快就能穿上干净的衣服了
Everybody's gonna have clean clothes soon.
修理工应该今天早上十点
The repair guy's supposed to come today
到下午两点间过来
between 10:00 and 2:00.
亲爱的  你能在家里等他吗
Oh! Honey, can you be here for that?
我能坐在空荡荡的房子里等人吗
Can I sit around in an empty house and wait for someone?
亲爱的  我可是房产经纪人
Baby, I'm a realtor.
有执照的  专门干这种事
I have a license for that.
你确定你不介意吗
You sure you don't mind?
去吧  忙你的吧
Go. Run your errands.
这样我正好可以开始洗这些盘子了
It'll give me a chance to get started on these dishes.
很好  走吧  卢克
Oh, good. All right, come on, Luke.
好  晚点见
All right. See you guys later.
盘子比我想象的多啊
Oh. More dishes than I thought.
那个千层面盘子一定很难洗
That lasagna's gonna be a tough one.
有人需要一把硬毛刷了
Somebody's gonna need a scrub brush.
你好
Hello?
什么
What?
不...是吧
No...way!
1988年6月10日
June 10, 1988.
卡拉・康坎农和我在公共泳池里
Carla Concannon and I spent the afternoon
玩了一下午
frolicking at the public pool.
后来在她家里  我们开始做羞羞的事
Later, at her house, things got private
那时还放着卡莉・西蒙的
while a 45 of Carly Simon's
《没人做得更好》的45转黑胶
"Nobody does it better" played.
那是我第一次  也是她第一次...
It was my first time, her first time...
跟我做那事儿
with me.
我一直想要拥有那张45转黑胶唱片
I always thought it'd be fun to own that 45.
当那天早上唱片店终于给我打来电话
When the record store finally called that morning,
我立马跑了过去  以免错过修理工
I ran right down so I wouldn't miss the repairman.
我必须拥有那张唱片
I had to have it.
这是我重温
It was the chance to relive
那神奇的3分42秒的机会
those magical 3 minutes and 42 seconds,
这也正是那首歌的长度
which was also the length of the song.
但我突然间想到
But then it dawned on me --
我心想着那些
I was cheating on my wife
跟别的女人的热烈回忆是对我老婆不忠
with the red-hot memory of another woman.
我不能让克莱尔发现
I could not let Claire find out.
我得销毁证据
I had to destroy the evidence.
还好  我在重压之下依然冷静
Luckily, I'm cool under pressure.
什么  不
What?! No!
他什么时候
When did he...?
不是吧
Come on!
尽管障碍重重
There were a couple of snags,
但我觉得我隐藏得很不错
but I think I covered my tracks pretty well.
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：亲爱的小饭  冰蓝  罂粟无果  Ethan-泽生  丁小七
时间轴：木瓜一号   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第二十一集
很抱歉这么久才把这些衣服拿给你
I'm so sorry it took so long to get you these clothes.
我把它们落在车后座了
I left them in the back of my car
而且完全忘了
and completely forgot about them.
听着好耳熟
Sounds familiar.
我才进药店三分钟
I was in the pharmacy for three minutes.
车窗开了一道缝  还给你留了果汁
You had a cracked window and a juice box.
别再说那件事了
Let's retire that story.
我能穿这件拍全家福吗
Can I wear this for the family photo?
亲爱的  这件衣服很可爱  但是
Oh, honey, that's adorable, but, you know,
歌洛莉亚要我们穿牛仔裤配黑T恤
Gloria wants us in jeans and a black T-shirt --
经典又随性
Classic and casual.
也许拍完照后  我们可以顺便
And then maybe afterwards, we can stop by
去帮高中话剧表演换布景
and change the scenery in a high-school play.
这条裙子真的很可爱
That is a really cute dress.
是啊  谢谢  昨天刚买的
Oh, yeah, thank you. Just got it yesterday.
真的吗
Really?
让我想起了我六个月前给你的东西
It reminds me of something I gave you six months ago.
你让她穿过二手衣服吗
Do you ever put her in the girls' hand-me-downs?
-有啊  一直都有  -真的吗
- Oh, yeah. All the time. - Really?
因为如果你不喜欢我女儿们的衣服
Because if my girls' old clothes aren't to your taste,
我也可以...给别人啊
I could always just... give them to somebody else!
冷静点  克莱尔
Okay, calm down, Claire.
你的声音高得都快吵到我家的猫了
Your voice is getting to that pitch that disturbs our cat.
我的天呐
Oh, my God.
你们肯定不敢相信老爸说了什么
You will not believe what dad just said.
我们在商场里
So, we're at the mall, right?
那里有架钢琴  我坐在旁边的椅子上
And there's a piano there. I sit down behind it.
-我开始  -拜托  米奇尔
- I start... - Come on, Mitchell.
他就是不太会表扬人
He's just not wired for compliments.
我相信你一定弹得很好
I'm sure your playing was great.
我根本不会弹钢琴  我从来没学过
I don't play the piano. I've never taken a lesson.
-你确定吗  -天呐
- Are you sure? - Oh, my god.
我自己的家人都不了解我
My own family doesn't even know me.
米奇尔  拜托  别这么敏感
Mitchell, please. Don't be so sensitive.
你看我都没有因为
You don't see me pitching a fit
小卡这么势利不愿接受我们的
because Cam is too much of a snob
二手衣服而生气发火
to use our hand-me-downs.
势  抱歉  势利
Sn-- I'm sorry -- snob?
我告诉你  我来自质朴的农村家庭
I will have you know I come from simple farm folk.
手指甲里永远有在土地里
There is permanent dirt underneath
劳作时留下的泥土
these fingernails from working the soil.
真的吗
Really?
我还不知道给兰花换盆
I had no idea that re-potting your orchids
也算是在土地里劳作呢
counted as "Working the soil."
兰花是种在土里的
Okay, they're in soil, are--
知道吗  我不想讨论这事了
You know what? I don't want to talk about this.
我没必要听这些
I don't need to listen to this.
我要出去透透气
I'm gonna go out and get some air.
我知道那种感觉
I know the feeling.
别再提了  真的
Retire it. Seriously.
你看乔是不是有点脸色苍白
Does Joe look a little pale to you?
这个国家的人在我看来都脸色苍白
This whole country looks pale to me.
今晚就要拍照了 我觉得他脸上应该多点颜色
I think he needs a little color for tonight's photograph.
你觉得使用美黑喷雾的最小年龄是多大
What do you think is the minimum age for a spray tanning?
既然乔出生了
Now that Joe is here
他的头也终于是正常大小了
and that his head is finally normal-shaped,
我决定照一张新的全家福
I decided to take a new family portrait.
好啊
Hola!
购物怎么样
How did it go at the mall?
买了一件衬衫  惹怒了我儿子
Bought a shirt, angered my son --
又是一次成功的外出
another successful outing.
我一直想这样做
Ooh. I've been wanting to do this.
快回答  天使头上那个环是什么
Quick -- what's the ring around an angel's head?
-什么  -好啊[光环]
- What? - Halo!
你说了天使那个梗
You did the angel one!
一般情况下我会很高兴
Ordinarily, I'd be delighted,
但这次聊天不会有趣了
but this isn't gonna be one of our fun chats.
你是说像你看见小型飞船时
You mean like that time you called me
给我打电话的那次吗
when you saw that blimp?
它飞得好低  上面的人都冲我挥手了呢
It was so low, they waved back.
我做得很好
I'd done a pretty good job
清除了那张唱片的一切痕迹
eliminating all traces of that record,
但是还有一个问题
but there was still one loose end.
今天早些时候
You know, earlier today,
我们在街上碰见了
when we ran into each other on the street?
我没看见你  你也没看见我
I didn't see you. You didn't see me.
你这是说
Okay, so you're saying
不管我们中的一个在干什么
whatever either one of us might have been doing
这将永远...
will remain forever --
我没看见你  你也没看见我
I didn't see you. You didn't see me.
说清...  喂
Just to be c-- hello?
杰真酷  他明白
Jay's so cool. He gets it.
我不知道他在说些什么
I didn't know what he was talking about,
但我得让他闭嘴
but I needed him to keep his trap shut.
最近  我可能在忙活
You see, lately, I may have been dabbling
像我这样强壮的爷们儿
in something that... strong, virile men like me
不该忙活的事
aren't supposed to be dabbling in.
这不符合我的形象
And it wouldn't exactly fit my image
如果人们发现我打算
if people found out I was considering entering...
带一只可爱的小狗参加狗展
a certain adorable dog in a dog show.
爱心宠物狗
歌洛莉亚觉得我是出去轮换车胎了
Gloria thought I was out getting my tires rotated.
其实  我是在给斯黛拉买装饰领结
Actually, I was buying Stella a decorative show collar --
以防万一嘛
you know, just in case.
我想着如果她看起来很漂亮
I figure if she looks beautiful,
就会更自信
she'll feel beautiful.
猜猜我们在图书馆碰上了谁
Guess who we ran into at the library.
我怎么知道  我一直都在这里
How would I know? I was here the whole time.
桑杰・帕特尔  他拿到了克罗恩氏病
Sanjay Patel. He's got Crohn's disease.
-不是吧  -就是啊  太走运了
- No! - I know. So lucky.
他绝对会获得科学奖学金的
He's totally going to win that science scholarship.
他该用这笔钱来治秃头
He should use it to find a cure for baldness,
因为他都16岁了  还用梳发盖秃头
'cause that kid is 16 with a comb-over.
就这样
That's it!
我得选个新主题
I'm just gonna pick a new topic.
我要一种学校里所有人
I want a disease that everyone in the school
都会讨论的疾病
is going to talk about.
好吧
All right!
你站在这里干什么
Why are you standing there?
因为我好想你  我好爱你
'Cause I missed you. I love you so much.
我也爱你
Oh, wow. Love you, too.
修理工修得怎么样了
How'd it go with the repair guy?
修理工来了  但我错过了他
The repair guy came, but I missed him.
"为什么  你在干什么"
"Why? What were you doing?"
"听唱片"
"Listening to a record."
"什么唱片"  "不重要"
"What record?" "It's not important."
"菲尔"
"Phil!"
"我第一次滚床单时的背景音乐
"The soundtrack to my first sexual experience
我时不时就会想起那个经历
that I think about from time to time.
亲爱的  你要去哪  别带走孩子们"
Honey, where are you going?! Don't take the kids!"
他没来
He didn't show up.
什么  太过分了
What?! That is so annoying!
就是啊  放下你的杂物
I know. Put away your groceries.
我打电话给他重新安排
I'll call him and reschedule.
不行  你太善良了
No, no, no, no, no. You are too nice.
我去打电话
I am calling.
不弄清真相我绝不善罢甘休
I am not resting till I get to the bottom of this.
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
这又不是我第一次被男人放鸽子了
It's not the first time I've been stood up by some guy.
听听你自己在说什么  菲尔
Oh, listen to your words, Phil.
是啊  是啊
Yep. Yep.
她说我是势利眼  米奇尔
She called me a snob, Mitchell.
真抱歉  我没有热心地把莉莉
I'm -- oh, I'm sorry if I don't rush
塞进克莱尔扔给我们的
to throw Lily in every bargain-bin rag
廉价衣服里
Claire tosses our way.
你这样说还是很势利眼啊
You're not really shedding the "Snob" tag with that.
为了今晚的拍照
Look, why don't we just put Lily
不如我们让莉莉穿上艾丽克斯的衬衫吧
in one of Alex's shirts for the picture tonight?
她会看穿的
She'll see right through that.
不  你想的是海莉的衬衫
No, you're thinking of Haley's shirts.
不  我是说我们这样做看起来
No, I mean it'll look ke we're doing it
就像是因为她提到了这事
just because she brought it up.
我知道  所以我在找一张莉莉穿着
Well, I know. That's why I'm looking for a photo
别人的旧衣服的照片给卡莱尔看
of Lily in a hand-me-down to show Claire,
但我好像找不到
but I-I can't seem to find one.
顺便说一句  这些照片里基本都没我
By the way, I'm barely in any of these.
米奇尔  你的建议是我想的那样吗
Mitchell, are you suggesting what I think you're suggesting?
是啊  有时我觉得我们家不关注...
Yes! Sometimes I feel like this family looks right past --
你在建议我们筹划拍一组照片
You're suggesting that we stage a photograph.
给莉莉穿上旧衣服
Put Lily in some hand-me-downs.
让照片看起来像是以前照的
Make it look like it's from the past --
比如说圣诞节  来证明克莱尔错了
Christmas, say -- just to prove Claire wrong.
简单易行
Simplicity itself.
那根本不是我的意思...
That's not remotely what I'm saying --
米奇尔  不要怀疑自己了
Mitchell, don't second-guess yourself.
这简单易行
It's simplicity itself.
是啊  再说一次  我想和主管谈谈
Yes, once again, I would like to speak to a supervisor.
如果我丈夫说没人来  那就是没人来
Listen, if my husband said nobody came, nobody came.
爸爸  该你走了
Dad, it's your move.
不  我想我现在应该保持冷静
No, I think I should just play it cool for now.
对不起
I'm so sorry.
搞定了
Score!
我找到了一个既稀有又有趣的疾病
I got a disease that's rare and fun
嗜睡症
-- narcolepsy.
公司发誓说司机十点来过这里
The company swears that the driver was here at 10:00.
他们在叫司机接我电话
They're putting him through to me right now.
我要驳倒他的说法
I'm gonna chip away at his story.
看看你怎么脱身吧
Let's see how you get out of this.
我在思考啊
I'm thinking.
这是一种精神病
It's a neurological condition
病人会在极端压力下睡着
where people under extreme stress actually fall asleep.
就像大脑的一种逃脱方式
It's like a way for the brain to escape.
我打赌他做了什么不该做的事情
I bet he was doing something he shouldn't have.
我就让他一直说到露出破绽为止
I'm just gonna let him keep talking till he makes a mistake.
每个人都会犯错
Everybody makes mistakes.
套索收紧
And the noose tightens.
我的耳机怎么跑到沙发上去了
Why were my headphones in the couch?
很好  你们留有所有司机的定位记录
Oh, good. You do keep GPS logs on all your drivers.
逃不出去了
There's no way out.
我先把你的名字记下来
Let me just write down your name.
谁还需要这张反面唱片店的收据吗
Hey, does anybody need a receipt from Flipside Records?
去他的
Damn it!
我连这个都没看见
I didn't even see that!
我看到你报名了今晚的表演
I see you're registered for tonight's show.
第一个上场是吧
First one, huh?
是的
Yeah.
大庭广众之下
I'm not sure I'm comfortable
在一个圈里蹦蹦跳跳这种事
with that whole prancing-in-a-circle thing
我觉得不太舒服
in front of everybody.
能找别人带她完成表演吗
Can someone else run her through her routine?
必须是主人亲自带
It has to be the owner.
我想这是最好的  我俩有默契
I suppose that's the best. We have a rapport.
好的  五点见
All right. See you at 5:00.
五点
5:00.
我五点时家里有点儿事情
Uh, I got a family thing at 5:00.
这种活动一般会准时开始吗
Do these things tend to start on time?
当然了  这又不是猫咪表演
Of course. It's not a cat show.
好吧  我最好快去快回  走吧
Well, I better speed it along. Come on.
我真不敢相信妈妈让我带你来这里
I can't believe mom made me take you here.
这是我唯一的一件黑色衬衫
This is my only black shirt,
妈妈让我洗干净
and mom needs me to wash it.
只有当我看到穷人时
It's only when I see the less fortunate
我才意识到我的衣服有多幸运
that I realize how lucky my clothes are.
洗衣机都被占用了  我们只能等着了
All the machines are taken. We're gonna have to wait.
我才不要在这无聊的日光灯下
Oh, I am not spending any more time
浪费更多时间
in fluorescent lighting than I have to.
去把你的衬衫塞到别人的衣服里
You're gonna sneak your shirt in with someone else's load --
比如那个男的  走这边
Like that guy's. Go that way.
我去分散他的注意力
I'll distract him.
不好意思
Excuse me.
海莉
Haley?
我的天  凯文
Oh, my god. Kevin.
我的名字是基思
It's "Keith."
你真的不记得
You really don't remember
你在科切拉音乐节上抛弃的男生了吗
the guy you abandoned at Coachella?
我没抛弃你  我给你发信息了
I didn't abandon you. I-I texted you.
那个DJ简直把我催眠了
That deejay put me in a trance.
是嘛  有点儿像是
Yeah. It's -- it's almost
你为了要门票而利用我
like you were using me for tickets.
怎么可能
Oh. That's crazy.
你还能再弄到那个票吗
Can you get those again?
还是你叔叔只能帮那一次忙
Or was that just, like, a one-time thing with your uncle?
只有那一次
It was a one-time thing.
好吧  那么  很高兴见到你
Okay, so, good seeing you.
好吧
Yeah.
-提醒我千万别跟你约会  -想得美
- Remind me never to date you. - You wish.
拜托  我肯定能追到你
Please. I could totally get you.
我倒想看你试试呢
Like to see you try.
好了  莉莉  你能过来吗
All right, Lily, can you come in here, please?
已经到圣诞节了吗
It's Christmas already?
也许应该提前跟她说一声的
Probably should have prepped her.
行了  不  这不是真正的圣诞节
Okay, no, it's not actually Christmas.
我们只要拍一张好玩的照片
We're just gonna take a fun photo.
而且我得在照片里因为我属于这个...
Which I am going to be in because I am a member of the --
我的长筒袜呢
Where is my stocking?
淡定
Oh, relax.
它不在照片里  你也不在
It's not in the shot, and neither are you.
拿着  你在这里拍这张照片
Here -- I want you to take the picture from right over here.
这边  行  很好
This way. Okay, great.
莉莉  你去换上这身衣服
Lily, I want you to put this on
然后站在树前面  我们把照片一次搞定
and then stand in front of the tree, and we'll pop a shot off.
快看这些漂亮的礼物
Ooh! Look at all the pretty presents!
那些都是空盒子
Those are just empty boxes.
你要气死我了
You're killing me!
我不知道是哪一个
I don't know which one it is!
我没看见他放衣服进去
I didn't see him put it in!
等等  我想我找到了
Wait! I think I found it.
他来了
He's coming!
什么  不
What?! No!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我  我看见你的衣服洗好了
Uh, I-I saw that your laundry was done,
我想帮你叠好  这样我们就能把
and I was gonna fold it for you to make us even
你觉得我做了但其实我没做的事情扯平了
for what you thought that I did that I didn't do.
扯平
Even?
我拿着你的爆米花
I held your popcorn for eight hours
等了你八个小时
waiting for you to come back.
我把整个停车场转了两遍
I walked all the parking areas twice,
查看了所有的医用帐篷
checked every medical tent.
等我回来的时候
By the time I got back to my car,
我的车被砸了  电池被偷走
it had been broken into and the battery was gone.
我不得不用我的音乐节门票
I had to trade my festival pass
换一辆马拖车送我回家
for a ride home in a horse trailer.
可是
But...
看来某人拿到音乐会的纪念衫啦
Looks like someone got a concert t-shirt.
爸爸  有什么事情让你烦心
Dad, is there anything bothering you
导致你  也许是
that might be causing -- I don't know --
严重的心理压力吗
major psychological stress?
没有  我一直表现得很正常  不是吗
No. I've been acting normally, haven't I?
今天早些时候发生什么了吗
Did something happen earlier today?
什么都没有
Uh, nothing at all.
因为你看上去有点儿紧张
Because you seem a little tense.
什么  不  我没有  不要纠缠我
What? No, I don't! Stop badgering me!
我爱你妈妈  我们听音乐吧
I love your mom! Let's listen to some music.
天啊  你有时候编故事的方式
Boy, the way you cook things up sometimes,
有点儿...
it's a little --
-爸  -什么
- Dad! - What?!
你睡着了
You fell asleep!
已经是今天第五次了
It's like the fifth time today.
我觉得这跟没来修洗衣机的
I think it has something to do with that guy
那个人有关
not showing up to fix the washing machine.
事情不完全是这样的
Well, that's not exactly what happened.
你溜出去在反面唱片店
You snuck out to buy
买《没人做得更好》这首歌时
"Nobody Does It Better" from Flipside Records,
他来了是吗
and he showed up?
差不多是这样了
That's more exactly what happened.
你是怎么知道这些的
How do you know all this?
我观察你一整天了
I've been watching you all day.
我觉得由此产生的愧疚感让你昏昏欲睡
I think the guilt from that has been causing you to fall asleep.
那你知道卡拉的事了?
So you know about Carla?
现在知道了
I do now.
-爸爸  -到底怎么回事啊
- Dad! - What is happening?!
我原本还对穿牛仔裤和T恤衫表示怀疑
I was skeptical about the jeans and t-shirt,
但我挺喜欢的
but I like it.
摄影师能给我单独照几张吗
Any chance the photographer could fire off a couple solo shots?
看看乔的下半边脸
Look at the bottom of Joe's face.
怎么回事  你把他留在太阳下面了吗
What happened? Did you leave him in the sun?
没有  我带他出去呆了五分钟
No, I took him out for five minutes
好让他脸上有点颜色
to give him a little color.
我肯定忘了把遮阳罩全部放下来了
I must have not closed the visor all the way down.
他的肤色对你来说那么重要吗
Why is it so important to you that he has color?
因为我们要把照片
Because we're sending this picture
寄给哥伦比亚的家人
to our family in Colombia,
但我有个完全不像哥伦比亚人的儿子
and I have a son that doesn't even look Colombian.
到时候他们看到照片
Now they're gonna look at this picture,
肯定会觉得我这个当妈的不称职
and they're gonna think that I am a terrible mother,
居然连自己的小孩都照顾不好
that I can't even take care of my own child.
你的名声早就臭了
I think your reputation is set.
我现在还能做这个动作
I can still do this with my arm
因为我在水池里一直睡到三岁
'cause I slept in the sink till I was 3.
你好
Ha-lo!
人已经来了  我来照顾乔
People are here. I'll deal with Joe.
-好吧  -来吧  小宝贝
- Okay. - Come on, buddy.
起来咯
Ohh. Come on.
好啊  克莱尔还在路上
Hola. Claire is on her way.
爸  你得向妈妈坦白
Dad, you have to confess to mom.
消除愧疚感是唯一能解救你的办法
Clearing your conscience is the only way to make this stop.
真的吗
Really?
希望如此  不然我就得重写论文结论了
I hope so, or else I have to rewrite the whole end of my paper.
怎么只有你们俩  其他人呢
Just the two of you? Where's the rest?
我还想着五点前把照片的事解决掉呢
I had hoped to get this picture thing wrapped up by 5:00!
他们会各自过来
They're all coming separately.
小卡  帮个忙  打电话催一下米奇尔
Cam, do me a favor -- call Mitchell and light a fire under him.
我就在这儿呢  爸
I'm right here, dad.
好吧  我没看到你进来
Oh. Good. I didn't see you come in.
是你帮我开的门
You opened the door for me.
你还感谢我带了瓶雪当利酒过来
You thanked me for bringing a bottle of Chardonnay.
听起来不像我
Doesn't sound like me.
各位  我们到了
Hey, guys. We're here.
终于来了  快开始吧
Finally. Let's do this.
卢克你的黑T恤呢
Luke, where's your black shirt?
就在这儿  我去换上
Right here. I'll get changed.
好吧  快一点
All right. Shake a leg.
-你好  亲爱的  -你好
- Hey, sweetie. - Hi!
莉莉  小心点
Hey, Lily, be careful.
别弄脏了这么漂亮的衣服
Don't get anything on that beautiful outfit.
看到没有  是不是很眼熟
Recognize it? Look familiar?
我看到了  但我不觉得
Yes, I do, but I hardly think
你们在我发完火之后再给她穿
that putting her in one of Alex's hand-me-downs
艾丽克斯的旧衣服能证明什么
proves anything after I pitched a fit.
首先  我认为你敢于承认
Well, first of all, I think it's really healthy
自己发了火真的很不错
that you do admit it was a fit.
但如果你还需要别的证明
But if you need further proof,
我肯定还能找到照片
I'm sure I could find a photograph over here.
没问题  找吧
Sure. Go ahead.
没我
No me.
找到了  去年圣诞节早上
Ah. There we are.Christmas morning last year.
天啊
Oh, my god.
是艾丽克斯的旧睡衣
Oh, it's Alex's old pajamas!
对不起  我该向你道歉
I'm so sorry. I owe you an apology.
有些时候我可能太
Sometimes I can be really --
那是什么
What's that?
挂历是十二月
Uh, the calendar opened to december,
给圣诞老人的饼干被吃了一半
the half-eaten cookies for Santa Claus,
给驯鹿的胡萝卜被啃过  哪里有问题
the nibbled-on carrots for reindeer? I don't know.
那不是上个月的《名利场》杂志吗
No, that looks like last month's Vanity Fair.
好莱坞的造型不就那么几种
Oh, well, you know, every month's "Young hollywood."
莉莉那颗牙不是刚掉的吗
Mm, and didn't Lily just lose that tooth?
不  牙还在  就是弄脏了
Nope, it's still there. It's just dirty.
圣诞节早晨吃的巧克力
Christmas-morning chocolates.
我很确定这个是米奇尔
Uh, and I am quite sure that's a reflection of Mitchell
穿着今早那套衣服的身影
in the clothes he was wearing this morning.
我终于出现在照片里了
Oh, yay, I finally made it into a picture.
你真是本性难移啊  是吧
Just couldn't change, could you?
你是个势利眼
You are a snob.
-你知道吗  -你是个势利眼
- Okay, you know what... - You're a snob.
就算不是势利眼也看得出
...it hardly takes a snob to recognize
-你给你的孩子们买的衣服  -势利眼
- the clothes you put your children in... - Snob!
顶多也就称得上普通
are uninspired at best.
-克莱尔  小卡  够了  -真的吗
- Claire,Cam, enough! - Oh, really?!
这家里每个人的品味都很棒
Everybody in this family has good taste.
只不过各不相同
It's just different.
这已经引发了太多争执
It's causing too many fights.
所以我今天才要求
That's why today I just put everybody
大家都穿简单的T恤和牛仔裤
in a simple T-shirt-and-jeans outfit.
现在开始定一条新家规
Mm. There's a new rule from now on --
谁也不能再给别人的小孩衣服
nobody gives clothes to anyone else's children.
我觉得这是最好的解决方案
Well, I think that's probably for the best.
感谢上帝乔这次生日我不用
Thank god I don't have to spend one more of Joe's birthdays
再那样尴尬地笑了
with a funny smile on my face.
谢谢你小卡  他很喜欢
Thank you, Cam. He loves it.
双胞胎哟
Twinsies!
好了  各位  要照相了
Okay, everybody, it's picture time.
卢克呢
Where's Luke?
在这儿呢
Right here.
宝贝  你穿的是什么  女生的T恤吗
Honey, what are you wearing? Is that a girl's shirt?
我貌似在洗衣房拿错了
I guess I grabbed the wrong one from the laundromat.
不过坦白讲我不讨厌这种贴身感
If I'm being honest, I don't hate the way it fits.
肯定是那家伙的女友的衣服
It must be that guy's girlfriend's shirt.
要是我说这样让对他更有兴趣了
Is it bad that that makes him
是不是不太好
more interesting to me?
是的  离他远点
Yes. Stay away.
不用担心卢克  我们可以让他站到后排
Don't worry about Luke. We'll stick him in the back row.
不是所有人都能被拍得好看的
Not everyone can look their best in the picture.
乔准备好了
Joe's ready.
你对他做了什么
What did you do to him?
你想让他看起来更像哥伦比亚人
You want him to look more Colombian.
没有比哥伦比亚国旗更合适的了
What's more Colombian than the Colombian flag?
太完美了
He's perfect.
今天对我的儿子们来说不是个好日子
Not a banner day for my male heirs.
克莱尔  你站到后面去
Claire, you're in the back.
菲尔  你站克莱尔后面  别乱比手势
Phil, you're behind Claire. No rabbit ears.
我不希望你在克莱尔背后玩什么花样
I don't want you messing around behind Claire's back.
卡梅隆  莉莉  快来
Cameron, Lily, come on in.
要照相了
It's picture time.
亲爱的
Honey.
我有点事想跟你说
There's something I need to tell you.
你知道人都会有一些
Uh, you know how you can treasure
想要珍惜的过去
special moments in your past
但绝不会因此影响现在的幸福
that in no way diminish the special moments in your present?
没错  亲爱的  那叫做回忆
Yeah, sweetheart, it's called having a memory.
希望我坦白的时候你态度能好一点
Okay, I wouldn't mind a friendlier tone as I move through this.
你做了什么
What did you do?
快  快  快
Up, up, up, up, ah!
走错方向了  宝贝
No, that's the wrong way, sweetheart.
莉莉的口袋里掉了什么出来
What fell out of Lily's pocket?
那是钻戒吗
Is that a diamond ring?
跟你的T恤肯定很配
Huh. That'll go great with your shirt.
看上去是真的
It looks real.
是真的
It is real.
有点小瑕疵但是颜色很正
A small occlusion, but very good color.
是克莱尔的
This is Claire's.
不是
No.
克莱尔的戴在她手上呢
Claire's got her's on.
菲尔  得了吧  你完全无法区分
Ay, Phil, please, you cannot tell the difference
这颗美丽但有点小的钻石
between this beautiful, but a small, diamond
和那一大块的玻璃仿制品
and that chunk of glass
那玩意儿几周前就该把她的手指勒断了
that should have made her finger fall off weeks ago.
我感觉我好像给你惹祸上身了
I feel like I am getting you in trouble.
拍照啦
Picture time!
怎么回事
What's happening?
好吧  你先别生气
Okay, don't be mad.
我几个月前把我的真戒指弄丢了
Um, I lost my real ring a few months ago,
我刚刚才意识到那肯定是掉进了
and I just realized it must have fallen
我送给莉莉的那一箱衣服里
in the box of clothes I gave to Lily.
你为什么要把戒指取下来
Why'd you take it off?
我开车被警察拦下了
Well, I got pulled over,
我想跟他调调情  让他免开罚单
and I wanted to flirt my way out of the ticket
于是假装我是单身
by pretending I was single
那方法起作用了  我还挺喜欢的
And it worked, and I kind of liked it.
然后我对这种喜欢产生了深深的愧疚感
And then I felt so guilty about liking it
于是我想把这全部的记忆都抹除掉
that I just wanted to erase the whole thing.
所以你撒谎了吗
So you lied?
是的  我撒谎了  我很抱歉
Yes. I lied. I'm sorry.
那是不是说明我是个很糟糕的人
Does that make me a terrible person?
不  不会  你在开玩笑吗
No, no. Are you kidding me?
我们已经结婚很久了
We've been married for a long time.
我们各自都有点小秘密也是很自然的嘛
Of course we're gonna have our little secrets.
重要的是
The important thing...
我们心里很清楚
...is that we know the difference
无害的放纵
between a harmless indulgence...
和真正放荡的区别
and a real indiscreet--
歌洛莉亚
Gloria?
-左边那枚  -谢谢
- Left. - Thank you.
好了  该拍照了
Okay, it's picture time!
大家都快点
Everybody, hury up.
赶快就位
Get in your positions.
都好了吗
All right?
很好  大家应该都到齐了
All right, I think that everyone is here.
准备好了吗
Okay, ready?
笑一个
And smile!
开什么玩笑啊
Are you kidding me?
没有一个人注意到我不在
Nobody noticed I wasn't here.
你们是怎么回事啊
What does it take with you people?!
乔  我的宝贝  你还好吧
Ay, Joe, my baby, are you okay?
好吧  好吧  或许只有那样
Yeah, yeah, maybe -- maybe that -- that's what it takes
你们才会注意到我
for you to pay attention to me --
像乔一样发一下脾气
Throw a temper tantrum like -- like Joe.
我也可以大发  雷霆
I could just throw a big...temper tantrum that --
把一切都弄得一团糟
Or if I make a mess of everything and...
我觉得你刚刚的火是冲着我发的
I feel like that was aimed at me.
你想谈谈这事吗
You want to talk about it?
不如我去弹弹钢琴消消火吧
Or I could just play some piano.
看来被我猜中了
So I'm in the ballpark.
听着
Look.
如果你有时候觉得我们没注意到你的存在
If it seems sometimes like we don't notice you,
那或许是因为我们正集中心思
maybe that is because we are focused...
处理我们各自愚蠢的问题
...on our own stupid problems,
你这人向来很稳重
And you're so steady.
你是说我很无趣吧
Oh, you mean boring.
-不是的  -就是的
- No. - Yeah.
冷静
Calm.
因为你是按照你想要的方式
Because you live your life
在过自己的生活
the way you want to.
实际上  你最近也激励了我
In fact, you inspired me recently.
怎么说
Oh, how so?
好吧
Fine.
我最近经历了一些事
I've been going through this thing lately.
一切都开始于我注意到
It all started when I noticed
有一群男人喜欢聚在公园的角落里
a group of guys in the corner in the park.
老实说  我最开始知晓他们在做什么时
And, uh, honestly, when I first found out what they were doing,
我觉得那很怪
I thought it was kind of weird,
但后来我发现我不停想着这事
but I found I kept thinking about it.
我觉得我该去尝试一下
And I thought I'd give it a whirl.
好吧  继续
Ok-- okay. Go on.
我觉得你应该能猜到接下来会怎样
I think you know where I'm going with this,
但是其中一个比我年长的家伙领我进了圈
but one of the older guys showed me the ropes.
不知不觉地
Next thing I know,
我每天都会去那个公园的那个角落
I'm hanging out at that park in that corner every day
并且很喜欢那种感觉
and loving it.
但我一定对此感到有些羞耻
But I must have also got some shame about it
因为我在做那事儿的时候
because it feels good
真的感觉很爽  但是
when I'm doing it, but...
那还是我吗
Is that me now?
带狗表演的男人
A guy with a show dog.
原来是这个啊
There it is!
好吧  我知道你不是去公园搞基
Okay, see, I-I knew what it wasn't.
我就是不知道你到底在干什么事儿
I just wasn't sure what it was.
实际上  现在就有一场表演
In fact, there's a show right now,
但是  我不去了
But...ah, I'm not gonna go.
不  不  爸
No, no. D--
-我可以看出来这事对你很重要  -不
- I could tell this is important to you. - No.
你该去  你该去
You -- you should go. You should go.
我不想偷溜出去
I don't want to sneak out,
我也不想其他人知道这事儿
and I don't want people to know about it.
爸
Dad.
一个睿智的人曾经跟我说过
A wise man once told me,
"我不理解这个
"I don't get it,
但如果那就是真实的你
but if that's who you are,
千万别为此觉得羞耻"
Don't you dare be ashamed of it."
我当时对待那事的态度真是很好
I did handle that kind of well.
是呀  是啦  好吧
Yeah, yeah, well...
那对我来说可不易
And it wasn't easy.
我从没想过我儿子会成为一名律师
I just never pictured my kid a lawyer.
让人们见到真实的你是很可怕的一件事
It's scary to let people see the real you,
即使是面对你最亲的家人亦是如此
even when those people are your own family.
但其实我们最不该担心他们的态度
But aren't they the ones we should be least worried about,
因为他们是不带偏见爱我们的人
the ones who will love us without judging,
他们会原谅我们的过错
who forgive our faults
庆祝我们的不完美
and celebrate our imperfections?
甚至会鼓励我们
Maybe even encourage us
尽情展现真实的自己
to let our true selves shine through?
等等  稍等一下
Wait, wait. Hang on. Wait, wait.
好了
Okay.
我觉得你看上去好漂亮
I think you look beautiful.
我看上去好老
I look old.
我所有的表亲都会看到的
All my cousins are going to see this.
点击一下那个按钮  把我的皱纹都修掉
Click the button that makes my wrinkles go away.
-出什么事了  -没什么
- What happened? - Nothing.
才不是没事呢  你都成跛子了
It's not nothing. You're limping!
你是不是又尝试跳俄式舞蹈来着
Were you trying to do the Russian dance again?
就是我在尝试的很愚蠢的举动
It was just something stupid I was trying out,
我也不知道为什么这样
and I don't even know why,
那几乎是不可能的
since it's basically impossible.
歌洛莉亚  歌洛莉亚  快看
Gloria. Gloria! Check it out.
这一定是你见过的最萌的事吧
Is this not the cutest thing you've ever seen?
它第一次尝试就成功了
She did that on her first try.
他也好喜欢
He loves it, too.
算你狠  乔  继续戳我痛处吧
Oh, oh, sure. Rub it in, Joe.
真棒
Attagirl!
它往我这边来了
Here she comes this way!
现在它就有点儿炫耀的意思了
Now she is just showing off.
我也是的
Both way.